Saturday Morning Musical Club records, 1909-1971 (bulk 1920-1948)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Saturday Morning Musical Club records, 1909-1971 (bulk 1920-1948)
AZ 443
This collection includes correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, financial records, and programs of the various civic events and artists' series performances sponsored by the Saturday Morning Musical Club, as well as similar materials related to the Temple of Music and Art.
Saturday Morning Musical Club (Tucson, Ariz.)
9.2 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The Saturday Morning Musical Club was organized in 1907 by Madeline Dreyfus Heineman. It began with twelve women performing at each others' homes but soon grew to include performances by well-known artists. The Club incorporated in 1917, and in 1927, the Club built the Temple of Music and Art to showcase these performances. The Temple of Music and Art, Inc. a non-profit corporation, was established by the Club in 1925 and closed its existence in 1961. The Club sold the building in 1972, but it continued as a non-profit organization.
Organization
This collection is organized into four series:
Series I: Saturday Morning Musical Club Records and Correspondence, 1911-1963
Series II: Temple of Music and Art Historical Items and Records, 1926-1963
Series III: Performance Records, 1909-1971
Series IV: Season Ticket Records, 1929-1963
Scope and Content Note
This collection includes correspondence, reports, minutes of meetings, financial records, and programs of the various civic events and artists' series performances sponsored by the Saturday Morning Musical Club, as well as similar materials related to the Temple of Music and Art.
Access Terms
Temple of Music and Art (Tucson, Ariz.)
Saturday Morning Musical Club (Tucson, Ariz.) -- Records and correspondence
Temple of Music and Art (Tucson, Ariz.) -- Records and correspondence
Music -- Arizona -- Tucson -- Societies, etc. -- History -- Sources
Centers for the performing arts -- Arizona -- Tucson -- History -- Sources
Women -- Societies and clubs
Tucson (Ariz.) -- History -- Sources
Programs
Correspondence
Bills
Container List
- Series I: Saturday Morning Musical Club Records and Correspondence, 1911-1963
  - Executive Board Minutes (2 volumes). 1911-1916/17 (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors Monthly Minutes (1 volume). 1948-1963 (Box 1)
  - Stock Receipts, no. 1-300. (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports. 1921/22-1931/32, 1943?, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - "State of the Union" document. 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Stockholders. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Stockholders Annual Meeting. 1929, 1948-1958 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Stock Certificates (including related correspondence). (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Memberships (4 volumes). 1915/16-1924/25, 1950/51-1953/54 (Box 2)
    See also boxes 20-22, Season Tickets.
  - Articles of Incorporation and By-Laws. 1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Includes correspondence with the Arizona Corporation Commission.
  - Property: "Cathedral Hall" on Ochoa St., Lot 11, Block 225. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence, taxes, bills, etc.
  - Property: South Stone and Scott, Lots 4 and 9, Block 231. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Includes correspondence, taxes, legal papers, etc.
  - Early rental of other buildings. 1912-1929 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous clippings and historical items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: General. 1920-1962 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence: Harry Berger. 1945-1953 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Samuel S. Berger regarding mortgage. 1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Tucson Chamber of Commerce. 1924-1929 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Arizona Federation of Music Clubs. 1918-1962 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: University of Arizona. 1927-1963 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Tickets and Memberships. 1918-1963 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Correspondence: Motion Picture Options. 1928-1930 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - B-Sharp Club. 1929-1934 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - La Campanella Club. 1925-1934 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Admission Taxes. 1919-1962 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Armistice Day Floats. 1921-1923 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Fund-Raising, Contributions, Gifts. 1922-1962 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Scholarships and music lessons. 1924-1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Stationery, forms, etc. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous undated items. (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Series II: Temple of Music and Art Historical Items and Records, 1926-1963
  - Miscellaneous historical items. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Arthur W. Hawes, Architect. 1926-1928 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Dedication. October 21, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Engraved Printer's Plates (3) used for the cover of the Dedication program. (Box 4)
  - Plates (4) of signatures and photograph used in the Dedication program. (Box 4)
  - Plate used for the program cover for Civic Concert, "In a Persian Garden." October 27, 1922 (Box 4)
  - Bills: General building repairs. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Bills: Cleaning. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Bills: Electrical work and supplies. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bills: Fire extinguishers, inspections, etc. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bills: Fish pond, patio, shrubbery, building exterior. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bills: Floor repairs. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bills: Furniture. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bills: Furnace, heaters, boiler. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Bills: Heating, fuel. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Bills: Janitor supplies. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Bills: Locks and keys. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Bills: Painting. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Bills: Plumbing problems. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Bills: Roofing. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Rentals: Tucson Symphony Orchestra. 1929-1937 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Rentals: University of Arizona Shaman Players. 1927-1930 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Rentals: Tucson Community Players. 1931-1933 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Rentals: Tucson Festival Society. 1959-1962 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Rentals: Miscellaneous correspondence. 1927-1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Rentals: Ledgers (6 volumes). 1927-1956 (Box 6)
  - Leases: Margaret Cusick School of Dancing. 1927, 1929, 1936-1939 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Leases: A. H. Yeomans, Motion Pictures. 1928-1930 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Leases: Tucson Fine Arts Association. 1929, 1932-1942 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Leases: Albert Stetson, Phoenix. 1933 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Leases: Monica F. Angulo, "El Charro" Cafe. 1933-1935 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Leases: Elizabeth Hawkey, Temple Hat Shoppe. 1935-1937 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Leases: Foster and Kleiser, billboard space. 1935-1949 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Leases: Seventh Day Adventists. 1936-1937, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Leases: Olive E. Leeke, Leader of Unity Center. 1936-1939 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Leases: Institute of Educational Music. 1936-1947 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Leases: Tucson Little Theatre. 1938-1946 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Leases: Inez Webster. 1947-1949 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Leases: Sarah Wilson & Edith Hickman, Tea Room. 1928-1929 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Leases: Roberta Humphrey, Dance Studio. 1934 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Leases: Arizona School of Arts and Crafts. 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Leases: William Strauss, proposed drama school. 1935 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Leases: Bunny Wheeler, Temple Fine Arts Gallery. 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Leases: Tucson Music Teachers Association. 1961-1963 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Mortgage: Chase National Bank and others. 1930-1960 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Banks: Arizona Trust Company. 1936-1960 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Includes correspondence regarding care of the Temple building during the summer of 1936.
  - Banks: Southern Arizona Bank and Trust Co. 1917-1929, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Banks: Miscellaneous. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Insurance Policies: American Insurance Company. 1947-1958 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Insurance Policies: Paramount Fire Insurance Company. 1945-1962 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Insurance Policies: Queen Insurance Company of America. 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Insurance Policies: United States Fidelity and Guaranty Company. 1945-1960 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Insurance Policies: Industrial Commission of Arizona. 1929-1963 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
  - Insurance Policies: Miscellaneous. 1918-1961 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Bond of Elizabeth Healy as Secretary-Treasurer. 1948-1961 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Contract with the Wage Scale Committee of Local no. 415 of the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees and Moving Picture Machine Operators of the U. S. and Canada. 1949-1958 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous legal papers. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Bills: Advertising, general. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Bills: Advertising, radio and TV. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Bills: Drayage. 1917-1961 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Bills: Flowers for special occasions. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Bills: Food, entertainment, gifts. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Bills: Organ repairs. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Bills: Piano purchase. 1927-1929 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Bills: Piano tuning and repairs. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Bills: Printing, El Tucsonese. 1919-1937 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Bills: Printing, F. E. A. Kimball. 1917-1933 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Bills: Printing, Acme Printing Co. 1934-1948 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Bills: Printing, various firms. 1939-1962 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Bills: Miscellaneous. (Box 9, Folder 14)
    Includes Berger Plaque, name plates for backs of seats in the auditorium of the Temple and storage rental, 1939.
  - Financial Reports: Various. 1913-1962 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Financial Reports: Monthly. 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Audits (not complete). 1922-1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Ledgers (3 volumes). 1917-1928/29. (Box 10)
  - Ledgers (2 volumes). May 1934-March 1946 (Box 11)
  - Ledgers (2 volumes). April 1946-March 1956 (Box 12)
  - Ledgers (2 volumes). April 1956-May 1963 (Box 13)
- Series III: Performance Records, 1909-1971
  These files contain the correspondence and bills relating to each performance. Additional programs for 1911-1916/17 will be found pasted in the two volumes of Executive Board Minutes in Box 1.
  - Civic Concerts and Programs, 1909-1963
    - Civic concerts and programs. 1909-1937/38 (Box 14, Folder 1-6)
    - "Il Trovatore." March 8, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "Cavalleria Rusticana" and "I Pagliacci." March 6, 1936 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      Includes also correspondence regarding a proposed performance of "Carmen."
    - Civic concerts and programs. 1938/39-1940/41 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Cavalleria Rusticana." March 29, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Civic concerts and programs. 1941/42-1943/44 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "The Warrior's Husband." July 9-11, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Civic concerts and programs. 1944/45-1962/63 (Box 14, Folder 13-15)
  - Artist Series, 1913-1971
    These files contain programs, correspondence, contracts, photographs, advertising, various financial records, etc., relating to each performance.
    - Madame Schumman-Heink (contralto). December 1, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Zoellner String Quartette. February 4, 1914 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Havrah Hubbard Operalogue "Falstaff," with Claude Gotthelf. December 20, 1916 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Norma Gould Dancers. November 24, 1919 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Rudolph Reuter (pianist). November 12, 1920 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - New York Chamber Music Society. February 17, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Frances Alda (soprano). March 21, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Margaret Matzenauer (contralto), Charles Carver (basso), and Frank LaForge (composer-pianist). March 28, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - New York Philharmonic Symphony Orchestra, Joseph Stransky conductor. April 18, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Zoellner String Quartet. December 12, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Sophie Braslau (contralto). February 28, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Geraldine Farrar (soprano). September 21, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Marguerite D'Alvarwz (contralto). November 24, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Louis Graveure (baritone). December 29, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Efrem Zimbalist (violinist). February 8, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Flanzaley Quartet. April 2, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Griffes Group: Lucy Gates (soprano), Olga Steeb (pianist), and Sascha Jacobinoff (violinist). January 22, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Anna Case (soprano). February 11, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Mario Schamlee (tenor). April 4, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Louis Graveure (baritone). October 20, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Ignace Jean Paderewsky (pianist). February 25, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Sousa's Band. January 10, 1922 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - "Cosi Fan Tutte," Hinshaw Opera Co. February 28, 1923 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Mischa Elman (violinist). January 2, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Denishawn Dancers. January 8, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Cherniavsky Trio. January 26, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Serge Rachmaninoff (pianist). February 2, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Florence Easton (soprano). February 23, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Rosa Ponselle (soprano). March 20, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Sousa's Band. January 3, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "La Traviata," San Carlo Opera Co. January 15, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "Marriage of Figaro," Hinshaw Opera Co. February 5, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - John McCormack (tenor). February 18, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Indian Tribes in Song and Story: Homer Grunn (composer-pianist), and Evalyn Bentley (lecturer). February 26, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Charles M. Courbin (organist). March 19, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Tipica Orchestra of Mexico. April 24, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Amelita Galli-Curci (coloratura soprano). November 29, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Mordkin Ballet. January 3, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "Rigoletto," San Carlo Grand Opera Co. January 13, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Tipica Orchestra of Mexico. April 24, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Will Rogers. March 2, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "The Beggar's Opera." November 22, 1927 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Creatore and his Band. January 20, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Madame Schumann-Heink (contralto). January 28, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Os-ke-non-ton (Indian baritone). (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Sigrid Onegin (contralto). March 12, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Sousa's Band. October 27, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Arthur Schmitz (pianist). November 30, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - "Rose Marie." December 31, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Doris Niles Ballet. January 28, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Mildred Titcomb (pianist). February 15, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Geraldine Farrar (soprano). March 12, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Royal Belgian Band. April 1929 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - "Polly," Beggars Opera Co. December 11, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Sir Harry Lauder and Company. December 5, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Mary Lewis (soprano). December 12, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Lawrence Tibbett (baritone). January 27, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Tito Schipa (tenor). February 6, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Kreutzberg and Georgi (dancers). February 15, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Dino Borgioli (tenor). November 26, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "Journey's End." April 9, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Fritz Kreisler (violinist). November 18, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Clare Clairbert (soprano). December 9, 1930 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Kreutzberg and Georgi (dancers). February 2, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - "Die Walkuere," German Grand Opera Co. February 4, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Cherniavsky Trio. April 14, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Vasily Gromakovsky (baritone). May 7, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - "Street Scene," (canceled). January 16, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - United States Army Band. October 15, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Carola Goya (Spanish dancer). November 23, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - "The Vinegar Tree," with Billie Burke. December 4, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Richard Crooks (tenor). December 5, 13.1 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Hart House Quartet. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Luboviski Trio. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Kreutzberg Dancers. March 26, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Walter Hampden in "Cyrano de Bergerac." March 5, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - "House Beautiful," (canceled). March 10, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Hall Johnson Choir. November 10, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Clair Clairbert and D'Arkor (coloratura soprano and tenor). December 2, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Thelma Given (violinist). January 27, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Don Cossack Chorus. February 7?, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Jose Mojica (tenor). February 10, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - "The Bad Man." May 9, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Sir Harry Lauder. December 13, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Walter Hampden in "Caponsacchi." March 22, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Bartlett-Frankel String Quartet. December 18, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Uday Shan-Kar and Company (Hindu dancers and musicians). January 3, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Vienna Choir Boys. January 13. 1934 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - "A Night Off," Theater League, Inc. March 9, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Luisa Espinel (Spanish folk music and dance). December 5, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Elizabeth Rethberg (soprano). November 10, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Myra Kinch and company of dancers. December 13, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - "Aida," San Carlo Grand Opera Co. January 30, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Paris Instrumental Quintet. February 27, 135 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Sidor Belarsky (basso). January 10, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Maria Isabel and Company (Spanish dancers) (canceled). January 10, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - "Faust," San Carlo Opera Co. February 4, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Jascha Heifetz (violinist). February 21, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Hollywood Symphonic Ballet. December 13, 1935 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Igor Gorin (baritone). November 19, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Col. W. de Basil's Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo. January 13, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Richard Crooks (tenor). January 30, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Sigrid Onegin (contralto). February 5, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Roth String Quartet. March 25, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Luther King (tenor). March 29, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - "Cosi Fan Tutte," Salzburg Opera Guild. January 2, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Jooss European Ballet. January 14, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Mischa Elman (violinist). March 15, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Igor Gorin (baritone). March 22, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - "La Boheme," San Carlo Opera Co. February 14, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Jessica Dragonette (lyric soprano). February 25, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Trudi Schoop and her Comic Ballet. March 8, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Ballet Caravan. November 21, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Curtis String Quartet. January 12, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Alexander Kipnis (basso). March 1, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Martha Graham and Company (dancers). March 6, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Russian Don Cossack Choir. January 19, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Tavo and Tanya (dancers). November 24, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Luigi Palazzi (tenor). February 6, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - "La Traviata," San Carlo Opera Co. February 16, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Margaret Sittig (violinist). March 20, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - United States Navy Band. October 29, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - "Golden Boy." November 11, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - "The Master Builder," with Eva Le Gallienne. December 5, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - San Francisco Opera Ballet. January 19, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Luther King (tenor). March 1, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Fray and Braggioti (duo-pianists). March 11, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Igo Gorin (baritone). March 25, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Devi Dja and her Bali and Java Dancers. November 9, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Mary Shahan (soprano) and Robert Hawkinson (pianist). November 13, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Manuela del Rio and her Spanish Ensemble. January 17, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Don Cossack Chorus. January 28, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Ruggiero Ricci (violinist). February 10, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo. February 18, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Kirsten Falgstad (soprano). March 9, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Jascha Heifetz (violinist). January 26, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Jan Kiepura (tenor). March 2, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Horton Ballets." March 17, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Amparo and Jose Iturbi (duo-pianists). February 5, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Joseph Szigeti (violinist). January 15, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Robert O'Connor (pianist). February 1, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Ballet Theatre. February 15, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Helen Traubel (soprano). April 30, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo. December 7, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Anne Brown (soprano). February 5, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Bartlett and Robertson (duo-pianists). March 25, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Nelson Eddy (baritone). April 1, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Argentinita and Spanish Ensemble. November 24, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Don Cossack Chorus. November 28, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo. December 12, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Compinsky Trio. January 27, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Conrad Thibault (baritone) and Robert O'Connor (pianist). March 1, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Bartlett and Robertson (duo-pianist). April 3, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - "Carmen," San Carlo Opera Co. January 54, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Bidu Sayao (soprano). February 26, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Ruth St. Denis (dancer). November 19, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Egon Petri (pianist). November 26, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo. December 11, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Bronislaw Huberman (violinist). January 30, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - San Francisco Opera Ballet (cancelled). February 4, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - The Theatre of Anga Enters. March 26, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Lupita Castro and her Mazalteco Group. March 27, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Carmen," San Carlo Opera Co. February 17, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "Madame Butterfly," San Carlo Opera Co. February 18, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Martha Lipton (contralto) (cancelled). February 24, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Thomas L. Thomas (baritone). March 23, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Ballet Ruse de Monte Carlo. December 10, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Bartalini (singer, actor, dancer). January 28, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Father Flanagan's Boys Town Choir. October 27, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Jan Peerce (tenor) (cancelled). November 4, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Ballet Russe de Monte Carlo. December 9, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - "Arms and the Man," Barter Theatre of Virginia. December 18, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Artur Rubinstein (pianist). January 7, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Percy Grainger (pianist). February 26, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Nelson Eddy (baritone). March 4, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - "La Boheme," San Carlo Opera Co. (cancelled). March 24, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Robert Brereton (pianist). March 19, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Rhythms of Spain (Spanish ensemble). November 29, 1948 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Marimi del Pozo (coloratura soprano). January 3, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 15)